&gt;&gt; Hello!
&gt;&gt; 大家好
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
Thanks for being here.
感谢大家来听演讲
Thanks for spending part of your
感谢大家选择在 WWDC
WWDC with us, talking about
与我们共度一段时光来聊聊
teaching with Swift Playgrounds.
用 Swift Playgrounds 进行教学
My name's Bill Dudney, I'll be
我的名字是 Bill Dudney  稍后
joined shortly by my colleague,
我的同事 Elizabeth 也将上台
Elizabeth, to talk about
和大家分享一些
teaching with Swift Playgrounds.
用 Swift Playgrounds 教编程的技巧
So, you might have noticed, over
大家可能已经注意到了
the last few years we started
过去的几年中我们发起了
with Hour of Code, and even some
比如"编程一小时"活动甚至
initiatives before that, that
之前也有一些类似的倡议活动
the whole world is now talking
通过这些活动现在渐渐地
about people learning about
全世界到处都有人在谈论
computational thinking, about
比如学习计算思维啦或是
how to program.
学习编程啦
In India, in Asia, and Africa,
印度有整个亚洲有非洲也有
and the United States.
还有在美国
There's big school systems like
也有像纽约和芝加哥这样的
New York and Chicago talking
大型教育系统在讨论
about teaching all of their kids
让所有的小朋友都能学会如何
how to code.
编程
Even heffalumps are learning how
如今连"长鼻怪"都在学习如何
to code.
编程了
Everywhere, everybody is
世界的各个角落都有人在
learning how to code.
学习如何编程
And, we are really excited about
看到这种景象我们当然非常开心
that.
这种体验真是太棒了能在这么一个
in a place where, to be in a
地方能经历这么一个时代
time, where everyone is starting
看到这么多人
to talk about coding.
都在讨论编程学习
So, our talk today is divided
我们今天的演讲大致
into two major sections.
分为两部分
The first one, I'm going to
上半部分由我来讲
cover, talking about teaching,
重点在教学方面
and then Elizabeth is going to
然后 Elizabeth 会上台
talk about designing and
与大家分享 Playgrounds 应用
implementing playgrounds.
具体的设计和实践
But, those two sections have
但这两个部分都包含着
three main pillars in them.
三项核心内容那就是
Goal, passion, and audience.
明确目标激发热情和了解受众
So, let's get started with
下面我就先讲
teaching, and specifically about
教学方面先从明确目标
the goal.
谈起
Now, as a teacher, you of course
当然作为教学者我们自身肯定
have to have a goal.
首先要明确自己的目标
What information is it that you
我们到底想要向学习者
want to impart to your learners.
传授些什么信息
But, equally important, is your
但同等重要的也要给学习者
learner's goal.
明确的目标
What is it that your learner is
学习者学过这些内容
trying to get out of that
到底该得到些什么
content?
收获
They need their goal to be front
我们需要在授课内容中时时刻刻
and center of the content so
把这个目标摆在醒目的位置
that they stay motivated,
这样才能激励学习者
because while learning to
毕竟尽管学习编程
program is not hard, it does
本身并不难但的确需要
take hard work.
经过一番努力
So, a place where I'm sure many
说到数学我相信很多人
of us have been with mathematics
都有过切身体会
is to either love it, or not,
有些人热爱数学有些人就不喜欢
and I'm sure we all have friends
我相信每人都有那么几个讨厌数学
who don't.
的朋友
As programmers, probably most of
当然身为程序员我相信这里
us are into mathematics.
大部分人都是喜欢数学的
We've at least played with it,
或者至少折腾过数学
and done some stuff with it.
或是以某种形式接触过
The people who don't get it
而那些无法理解数学之美的人
though, are often, or who aren't
其实经常是...  或者说那些
excited by mathematics are often
对数学没热情的人经常是
turned off by it, by some
因为一些个人的负面经历
experience where they end up
而丧失了热情比如上来就
with this long list of
面对这么一长串的
functions.
函数
Polynomials, trig, exponentials,
多项式啦三角函数啦指数函数啦
logarithms, their inverses.
对数函数啦它们的反函数啦
Solving for "x."
解出那个未知数 x
I remember, when I was younger,
我还记得在我更小一些的时候
and sitting in my geometry class
在几何学的课堂上
with my teacher, Mr. Carlin, I
我的老师叫 Carlin 先生
would ask him, probably once a
我经常问他可能一周就会
week, I was a real pest, "When
问一次我当时特别烦人问
am I ever going to use this?"
学这些东西到底有什么用
And, he would look at me and
他一般就看着我
say, "Please stop asking me that
说请你不要再问这个问题了
And, eventually, after I've
但后来在我烦了他
pestered him enough, he said,
超级多次之后他终于跟我说
"Look, you're probably never
听着你可能以后永远
going to use this, but it's
也用不上这些东西但学学
really cool anyway," and that
这些还是很好玩的这句话
sort of flipped a bit in my head
让我有点醍醐灌顶的感觉
to go from looking at math as
我以前看待数学都是当作
utilitarian, to looking at math
实用工具而之后却觉得数学
as something that's beautiful
可以很美很有趣
and fun to mess with, like a
学起来可以很好玩就像是
puzzle to solve.
解谜一样
And so, that really struck me,
他这句话让我突然开窍了
and it turned my direction away
也让我对数学的态度大有改观
from being frustrated with not
从觉得这东西不会有
having some practical
什么实际用途
application for it, to enjoying
而觉得无聊到单纯享受
it just to solve puzzles.
那种智力游戏的过程
Now, of course, little did Mr.
当然了当时 Carlin 先生
Carlin know, that I would
可想不到日后的我
eventually become a nerd, and
会最终长成一个书呆子
deal with geometry all the time,
然后天天要和几何学打交道
so thank you, Mr. Carlin, for
所以多谢了  Carlin 先生
teaching me geometry despite my
多谢您不顾我的抵抗依然教会了我
resistance.
几何学
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
So I have a couple of examples
当我试图给别人解释
that I use to try to explain
这个概念的时候我经常会
this concept to people, because
举这么几个例子因为我认为
I think it's so important that
当我们思考教学方法时
we think through this, when
让大家充分理解
we're thinking about teaching.
这个概念非常重要
Now, imagine you're trying to
我们想象一下如果
learn how to do art.
我们要学习怎样创作艺术作品
But instead of being artistic,
但却不从艺术角度入手
and spreading paint around a
不直接用颜料开始在画布上
canvas, instead, you're
进行创作而是
encouraged, or forced, to study
被鼓励或是说被逼迫从比如
the texture of colors, or the
颜料的质感入手学起
look of the color, or the shape
或者去学习颜色的感觉或者
of the brush, but never able to
笔刷的形状但从头到尾都没有机会
apply that paint.
真正下笔画画
It would be really hard to stay
要学习成为艺术家却不能
focused on learning to become an
亲手创作艺术这种学习过程
artist when you can't do art.
会很痛苦且容易分心
People want to create, they want
大家都想创造新东西
to build things, or they want to
都希望能够亲手搭建或制造
make things.
出成果
And, if you had to study that,
而如果我们从细枝末节学起
it would be very difficult to
就会让学习过程变得
get through it.
异常艰难
So much better to let people,
而一个更好的教学方法是
when they're learning to paint
比方说要学习绘画不如
to make a mess, smear the paint
就放任他们胡涂一气随心所欲
all over the place without
地涂抹颜料而先不要
concern, really, for what it
过多地去考虑成品到底
looks like.
好不好看
You can worry about that later.
那个我们可以稍后再考虑
Same thing with music.
对于音乐也是一样
Imagine if you had to know what
设想一下如果我们必须预先
every dot, every line, every arc
搞懂这张图上的每一个点每一条线
on this diagram meant before you
每一个弧度到底都是什么意思
could pick up a guitar, or start
然后才能拿起一把吉他
playing with your piano.
才能开始弹钢琴
It would be very difficult to
这个学习过程也会
get through all that.
非常艰难痛苦
So, I encourage people who are
所以我会鼓励那些想要进行教学
thinking about teaching to start
的人让一切教学活动
with a question.
以问题起始
That question is what drives the
这个问题会给你的
learner's goal.
学习者们设定目标
From that question, the learner
从问题入手可以让学习者
drives internal motivation to
内心产生足够的积极性
achieve the hard work of
进而激励着他们
learning the material you're
去主动学习消化你所想要
trying to get across.
教授的内容
Which brings us next, to the
这也就说到了下一点
audience.
了解受众
It is so important that we as
我们作为教育者必须要
teachers think through the
充分了解我们的受众
audience that we're aiming to
要清楚我们要教的人是
reach.
什么水平
Are they brand new coders?
他们在编程上完完全全是新手吗
Do they understand anything with
先前对编程有没有哪怕一丝一毫的
coding?
了解
Or, are they moderately
还是说他们已经
experienced and they're trying
有一些编程经验只是现在
to gain more insight into some
希望针对某一个特别的方向
particular piece of material?
再进行更深入地探索
You need to know who your
我们需要充分了解我们的
audience is and then make your
受众然后相应地更改内容
content communicate to them.
以便学习者能更快地消化理解
What I often see happening is
我们经常面对的一种情况是
people taking syntax and other
需要把一些大学里计算机
things from a computer science
科学专业教的东西比如句法
degree in college and then sort
或是其他什么东西然后
of moving it down to a level so
把这些东西进行拆解细化好让
younger people can understand
年龄更小的人易于掌握
it.
细化后手上就会有这么
cloud of concepts that you have
一大片的概念需要我们去
to get down, all these syntax
一一解释全都是和句法
items.
相关的
Now, of course, it's very
当然了这些的确
important that you understand
非常重要我们本来也需要
syntax, you can't code without
理解句法不知道什么是句法
knowing what syntax is, so in
我们也没法编程所以在
Learn to Code, the way we
"编程学习"里我们采取的
approach that, is that we build
教学思路是我们建立
this engaging world with these
这么一个迷人的世界其中
great characters and these silly
有着一些很棒的角色和一些
animations, and beautiful audio
逗趣的动画效果再加上完美的音效
to engage the learner so that
让学习者沉浸其中这样他们就
they'll go through the hard work
不太会介意下点苦功夫
of learning what a for loop is.
去学习 for 循环了
Here's an example of one puzzle
这是我们设计的智力游戏中
that we have that takes Byte
的一个例子学习者需要让 Byte
around the four sides of this
走遍这个四方小世界的
world, picking up gems.
每一个边收集宝石
In order to do that, you of
当然为了做到这一点我们
course use a for loop, and we
就需要使用 for 循环我们在
have that stated at the top of
页面上方也标明了这一点
the page, but that's not the
但使用 for 循环并不是
goal.
目标
The learner's goal is to pick up
对于学习者他们的目标是去
these items and to solve the
收集这些物品然后解谜
puzzle.
闯关
And so, we use that goal to
我们就可以利用这个目标
drive an internal motivation to
在学习者内心激发出积极性
go and learn what a for loop is.
让他们去主动学习 for 循环怎么用
The next step is often to dive
再往下经常就需要深入
into something like algorithms
到一些比如算法或是
and data structures.
数据结构这种东西
I love all these algorithms.
我好喜欢这些算法啊
Half of these names, I looked
这里一半多算法的名称我看着
and thought, Hmm, I wonder what
就在想唔不知道这又
that is, and I almost got
是个什么算法我跑去查了
distracted from prepping my
好一通 Soundex 具体是什么
slides by digging into what is
最后差点忘记了我幻灯片还没有
Soundex.
准备完
So--
话说回来
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
I don't know how many of you
我不知道在座有多少人
have interacted with younger
和比你们更年轻的人
people, but I doubt very
打过交道但我严重怀疑
seriously-- well, many of you
好吧其实你们很多人
are much younger than me, I
本身就比我年轻很多了
know, but I'm talking about
我知道但我说的意思是
young learners in school.
还在学校的青年学习者
How many of them have come to
这些人里有多少人是拿着
you with a bucket of integers
一大堆的整数跑来找你
and said, "You know, I really
然后说哎呀我真的
wish you would help me sort
好希望你能帮帮我把它们
these."
排排好啊
That's never happened.
不会有这种事的
No one wants to learn about
如果你要教整数排序没有人
sorting, they have a goal and
想学你需要给他们设立一个目标
sorting will help them achieve
然后让排序能够帮助他们达到
that goal, so you want to focus
那个目标所以我们需要格外
on the audience's goals and then
关注我们受众想达到什么目标然后
help them achieve those goals.
尽力去帮助他们实现这些目标
So, again back here to Learn to
所以让我们再回到"编程
Code, when we're talking about
学习"软件当我们谈到
algorithmic learning and
算法学习和
computational thinking, or when
计算思维的时候或是
we're thinking about using those
当我们考虑如何应用这些
concepts to teach people, we
理念去指导教学的时候我们
build this content like this
会把内容做成像这样的
same simple puzzle that we saw
简单明了的智力游戏就像刚刚
earlier, that's drawing the
给大家展示的会引导
learner in to thinking about
学习者主动地去思考
what an algorithm is, without
什么是算法哪怕我们根本
even using the word.
不提"算法"这个词
Then, later when we get close to
再往后一点等用户学到
the end of Learn to Code 1, we
"编程学习一"快结束的时候就会接触
approach this puzzle.
到这个智力游戏
This puzzle is a challenge page
这个智力游戏是个挑战页
and says to the learner, Hey, go
这个挑战项目会告诉学习者放开手
nuts.
做吧
Solve this in any way that you
你可以用你能想到的任何方法
want to in the most efficient
用你认为但凡可行的最高效的方法
way that you see possible.
来解决这个智力游戏提出的问题
But, this is after a long time
但学习者此时可是经历了长时间积累
of solving these puzzles where
已解过很多类似的智力游戏了
they start to understand and
他们在过程中已开始学会
think algorithmically, so they
如何使用算法来考虑问题了所以他们
look at this and think, Oh,
一看这个问题就会想好的
there's two diamonds, or there's
这里有两颗钻石或是这里有
two gems, and there's two things
两块宝石然后这里有两样东西
I need to flip.
我需要把这些开关打开
And, that's just programming the
而这些还只是开发过程中最
easy parts.
简单的部分
In the beginning, when I started
比如在我最开始刚刚开始
programming, I would not have
编程的时候如果那时叫我去
built the WWDC app, properly.
设计 WWDC 的应用一定设计不好
I wouldn't have made a table
我肯定不会去创建什么
view controller and a cell and a
表格视图控制器单元格或者
model.
模型
I would just dump all the code
我肯定是一股脑把所有的代码
into the view controller,
全都塞进视图控制器里
because I read MVC when I first
因为尽管我刚开始编程时就读了
got started, and I had no idea
MVC 框架但我当时根本没看懂
what that meant.
那都是些什么东西
Modeling is difficult, the
建模是很难的
syntax and the algorithms, and
而句法啊算法啊
so forth are the straightforward
这些东西反倒相对非常简单
So, another thing that I notice
所以这里我也注意到一点就是
that people get bogged down in
当人们思考怎样教授编程的时候
when they're thinking about
很容易就会在一些东西上卡住
teaching this stuff is, to focus
比如过于纠结于某些技术的
on details.
细枝末节
Now, of course, the details,
当然了这些细节
they're really important.
肯定的确非常重要
Several years ago, I thought, I
几年前我曾经想过
really want to learn to do 3D
我好想学习怎么做 3D
programming.
编程
I've always thought it's really
我一直觉得 3D 编程非常
cool, I love how fast it is, and
酷速度快还有并行性
the parallel nature of it.
我都很喜欢
So, I started diving into Open
所以我就去研究了一下 Open
GL.
GL
Bought a couple of books, and
买了几本书那几本书
without question, every one of
无一例外地每一本里
those books had this diagram in
都有这张示意图
it.
那么现在我就给大家
couple of seconds to look at
十几秒钟的时间好好看看
this diagram.
这张示意图
Study it hard, there'll be a
大家用心看之后会有
test.
测试
Now, here's a picture of a dog
好了现在这张照片上
playing with a computer.
有一只狗在玩电脑
Which one did you get more out
你们觉得从哪张图片上收获得更多
of?
[笑声]
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
So, when you're first getting
所以说当我们
started with 3D graphics,
刚开始接触 3D 图形学的时候
looking at this diagram, it's
就去研究这张示意图很难
very hard to make heads or tails
看明白这张图到底要说些什么
of it, you might as well be
与其琢磨这张图
looking at a picture of a puppy.
我们还不如去看一张
Instead, what we want to do, is
小狗图片而其实我们在教学时该做的
focus on fun.
也是注重乐趣
3D graphics is amazing.
3D 图形学多有趣啊
If I were teaching 3D graphics,
要是让我去教 3D 图形学
I would start with fun stuff,
我一定从有趣的东西入手
like Byte doing his silly dance,
比如我们看看 Byte 在这里蹦跶
He's fantastic, this is so
他看着多棒啊是不是很
great.
有趣
Now, of course, everything in
当然了这个示意图中
that diagram-- vertex shaders
的所有步骤比如 vertex shaders 啦
and primitive processing and so
primitive processing 啦这些
forth-- all of that is really
东西对于在屏幕上
important to getting every
生成出大家在屏幕上
single frame that you see happen
所看到的 3D 图像每一帧
on the screen, onto the screen.
这些步骤都至关重要
But, you never want to start
但我们不会希望从这些细节学起
You want to start with fun stuff
我们希望能先展示一个有趣的东西
to get people motivated instead
让学习者能有目标产生积极性
of bogging them down in details.
而不是上来就去纠缠一些细节
Finally, passion.
最后一点激发热情
You, as a teacher, as a
我们作为老师作为
developer, have passion for
开发者肯定是已经对
particular things.
一些事情充满了热情
You love some piece of computer
比如你可能喜欢计算机图形学的
graphics, or you love to think
某一部分或者你对
about UIKit, or ARKit, or
UIKit 或是 ARKit 充满热情
whatever, and you want to teach
不管是什么然后你要去教别人
Bring that passion in to how you
在思考教案的时候请务必记得
approach the teaching.
要把你的热情带入进去
You want to light the fire of
面对你要教的人你需要
that passion in the people
在他们的心里也激发出
you're trying to reach because
和你一样的对这些内容的热情
that's what will give them the
因为只有他们有热情
internal motivation to do the
内心才能有足够的积极性
hard work to learn what it is
去主动下功夫学习那些
you're trying to get across to
你想要教给他们的那些东西
them.
总结下用 Swift Playgrounds
Playgrounds.
进行教学
Focus on goal, audience, and
要明确目标要激发热情要了解受众
And, that's teaching.
这就是教学方面了
I'd like to invite Elizabeth
下面让我邀请 Elizabeth
onstage to talk through
上台给大家讲讲
designing Swift Playgrounds.
如何设计 Swift Playgrounds
Thank you.
谢谢大家
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Bill.
&gt;&gt; 谢谢 Bill
For that awesome introduction.
给大家带来如此精彩的介绍
I don't even know how to follow
我真不知道我能不能讲得比他
his jokes.
更加风趣幽默了
My name is Elizabeth, and I'm a
我的名字是 Elizabeth  我是一名
content engineer, writer, and
内容工程师作家还是
storyteller on the Swift
Swift Playgrounds 团队的
Playgrounds team.
一名叙事者
I'm really excited to be here
我很高兴今天能在这里
today, the last session of WWDC
在 2017 年 WWDC 的最后一场
2017 to teach you how to bring
演讲中教大家如何把刚刚
those ideals: goal, audience,
那三项理念明确目标激发热情
and passion into your Swift
和了解受众体现到我们的 Swift
Playgrounds.
Playgrounds 里
So, let's start at the
我们现在就从头
beginning.
说起
What is a Swift Playground?
Swift Playground 到底是个什么东西
Some of you, all our scholarship
在座有些人起码我们所有
students, know intimately what a
得奖学金的人肯定都谙熟
Swift Playground is, because you
Swift Playground 了因为今天能
had to make your own to get
来现场的肯定都是做过相关项目的
Others of you might have played
剩下的人可能自己上手
with these, might have learned
玩过也可能在刚刚开始
from one yourself, how the
编程的时候用这个软件
beginnings of coding.
学习过编程
A Swift Playground is
一个 Swift Playground
essentially a collection of
本质上就是一系列
pages, like this one.
像这样的页面
You can see on the left hand
我们可以在页面左手边
side, the prose section.
看到这是文本区域
At the top are the instructions,
左侧列在顶端的是说明指导
the story, whatever concept
编程背景和别的一些
you're trying to get across to
你希望向学习者传达的
your learners.
编程概念
This is where you're going to
我们就是在这个区域
teach them what they're about to
教给学习者他们需要做
do.
什么
On the bottom, on the right hand
在页面左侧这个区域的下端
side is the user code section.
用来供用户输入代码
This is the fun part where
这是真正有意思的部分
they're really going to be
学习者可以动手
creating, manipulating, trying
创作调整亲自尝试
out what you've taught them.
那些你刚刚教给他们的东西
And then on the right hand side,
而在页面右侧就是
the live view.
实时视图了
This is where you're going to
如果你有热情
bring your passion to this.
这就是你可以庆祝倾注热情的地方
Look how fun this world looks.
你看这个小世界看起来多有趣
I want to dive right in there
我都想一头扎进去
and learn how to code in Byte's
在 Byte 的小世界里学习怎样编程了
It's colorful, it's exciting.
多绚丽多激动人心
This is where the learner's code
学习者编写的代码也会在这里
is going to execute, where
显示出执行结果在这里他们
they're going to see what
可以直观地看到
they've created.
自己的创作结果
This is your point, to get them
这也是我们的目的让学习者
interested in whatever it is
能够对我们要教授的东西
you're trying to teach them.
产生足够的兴趣
In addition to these collection
除了这一系列组成
of pages that make up a Swift
Swift Playground 的基础
Playground, there are a few
页面我们还可以
other features that you can add
添加一些额外的特色功能
to make your experiences really
让用户的学习过程更佳
gripping.
引人入胜
There we go.
这样就好了
One of the first ones is
首先可以添加的就是
Cutscenes.
过场动画 (Cutscenes)
If you're familiar with the
对于那些熟悉
Learn to Codes, then you'll
"编程学习"的人可能已经
probably have seen some of
见过某种形式的过场动画了
We typically add them at the
我们通常把过场动画加在
beginning of new chapters, or
新章节的起始处或是加在
new sections, to introduce a
新模块的开头用这样一个
concept in a fun, animated way.
生动有趣的方式介绍一个新概念
These are written in HTML, and
这些过场动画是用 HTML 写的
they're a good way to introduce
如果你想在用户投入编程之前
a new topic before you dive
先给他们介绍一下新话题
straight into the code.
过场动画就是个很好的手段
Give the learner a sense of
可以在一开始就给学习者
where it is they're going.
树立一个比较明确的目标
You can also add hints to your
我们还可以在 Playground 手册里添加
playground books.
暗示帮助
These are so important for
这些也非常重要
giving the learner a contextual
暗示帮助可以给学习者一个大致的
sense of where they're going
背景概念让他们知道自己哪里方向
wrong.
不对
You can do a bit of
我们可以让软件
introspecting on the learner's
先检查一下学习者所编写的
code in order to figure out
代码找出他们到底在哪里
exactly what mistake they might
可能犯了什么错误然后
have made, and offer them
为他们提供量身定做
tailored help.
的暗示帮助
It's incredibly engaging to have
当一个软件能理解个体意图
software understand what you
并依此提供相应的反馈而不是
need specifically instead of a
对所有用户都一视同仁的时候
one size fits all sort of
这个使用体验是很
experience.
有吸引力的
So, use hints.
所以使用提示帮助吧
One thing to keep in mind with
但使用提示帮助时要记住的
hints is that some learners
一点是有些学习者非常
really don't like the extra
不喜欢接受额外的帮助
help, they want to do it
他们希望能独立
themselves.
完成解谜过程
So don't put essential
所以千万不要在提示信息中
information to solving the
泄露出任何过于
problem in here.
至关重要的信息
Make these real hints for those
只要给需要帮助的人一点点
who need them.
提示信息就够了
If hints aren't enough, you can
如果提示帮助还不够用我们也可以
also add solutions to your
在 Playground 手册里添加
playground pages.
完整的答案
These are essential.
这些也很重要
Think about the first time you
我们可以反思下自己第一次
were trying to learn a new
试图学习新技术时
technology.
的体验
Could you do it just with
别人只给我们解释一遍
someone explaining conceptually?
大致的概念我们就能够上手了吗
Or, did you need to look at a
我们是不是还需要看一个
reference example?
具体的应用实例
These are so helpful for your
这些答案对于那些一时卡住的
learners that get stuck and
学习者很有帮助比如有些人
aren't sure of the syntax,
一时不确定句法啦
aren't sure how to go on.
或者不太明白接下来该干什么啦
The solution gives them that
这种时候他们所需要的帮助可能
help they need.
就是一个直接的答案
Otherwise they might get
不然这些学习者可能就会
frustrated and leave your
非常沮丧然后直接
playground book entirely.
离开我们的 Playground 手册
You can also add assessments at
我们还可以在最后添加一个代码评估功能
These typically pop up once the
一般来说在学习者完成了你给
learner has completed the task
他们设置的任务后就会
that you've set them.
弹出这么一个窗口
You can also customize these
我们还可以定做这里的显示信息
depending on how your learner
根据学习者解决问题的不同方法
has solved the puzzle.
显示不同的反馈信息
Maybe you wanted them to use for
比如你可能希望学习者使用 for 循环
loops, but they used repeated
来解决问题但他们却只是重复了
code instead.
几遍代码
Now's your chance to suggest to
我们就可以用代码评估信息
them, great job, you completed
反馈给他们说做得好你成功完成了
the puzzle, but maybe next time,
智力游戏但下次遇到这种问题时
use a for loop instead.
不如试试 for 循环
It's a little bit better of a
可能会是更好的编程
paradigm.
范式
Alright. So we're all set,
好了现在万事俱备了
right?
是不是
We know about pages, we know
我们已经了解了页面了解了
about assessments and hints,
代码评估和暗示信息功能
it's coding time.
该开始编程了吧
Not so. We went ahead to the
先别急我们现在需要回到绘图板
drawing board.
从头再来
Literally.
真的回到绘图板
These are some of my actual
这里是一些我在设计
notes in the actual notebook
Swift Playgrounds 时
that I keep when I'm designing
画在笔记本里的一些
for Swift Playgrounds.
真实的笔记
Quick sketches, just getting
一些随手的草图就是
thoughts out of my brain onto
把脑中的想法简单地画到
the paper.
纸上
I might have a thought while I'm
也许是我通勤的时候产生的一些
riding the shuttle, or in the
突如其来的想法或者
shower, and I just want to get
洗澡时想到的我只要先随手
that down somewhere so that I
把想法记下来具体怎样实现
can iterate on it later.
可以以后再考虑
Starting out writing code, is a
如果构思原型的时候就开始编程
really expensive way to
是个非常浪费精力
prototype.
的事情
You might spend weeks getting a
那样的话很有可能花了好几周时间
cool working demo ready, and
好不容易做出一漂亮的样品程序
then show it to a potential
但在你给潜在学习者展示
learner, and they are totally
的时候却发现他们完全
lost, or they think it's boring.
看不懂或者觉得做得很无聊
Well, now you're stuck and you
那这样的话你就很尴尬了
have to redo all of those weeks
你还得回去返工之前几周的代码
of coding work.
也都白写了
Instead, start with cheap
所以构思原型的时候用个不
prototyping.
那么费力的方法
It's just as easy to show a set
在这种初始阶段我们
of storyboards on a whiteboard,
完全可以用白板或者甚至
or in a KeyNote even, to some
用 KeyNote 来展示我们
potential learners, to some of
构思的故事板然后拿去
your colleagues to get feedback
给潜在学习者或者你的同事们看
in that initial stage.
就可以得到有用的反馈
So we're all set now.
好了现在都准备好了
We've got the main parts of the
我们考虑好了 Playground 手册
playground book in mind, we
的主要部分我们
understand we want to start out
了解了应该选一个快速
with cheap, fast prototyping, so
易做的方法来构建原型
now let's take those ideals that
我们现在就可以把 Bill 刚刚
Bill taught us about, and put
教给我们的那些理念
them into practice.
付诸实践了
What is the learner's goal?
所以学习者的目标到底是什么
I want to take a minute here to
我现在想花几分钟时间
help you separate in your minds
帮大家在脑中区分一下
the actual different goals that
目前摆在我们面前的几个
are going on.
截然不同的目标
There's your goal as the author.
我们作为编写者有我们自己的目标
What do you want your learner to
我们希望学习者从整个 Playground
get out of the whole playground,
体验中取得什么样的收获
and of each individual page?
从每个单独的页面中收获什么
Those are separate goals.
这已经是两个不同的目标了
Your learner, as well, has a
对于我们的学习者也是一样
goal on a per-page basis, and
每页都有不同的目标然后整个
throughout the whole playground
Playground 手册做下来还有个整体
book.
目标
For example, in Cipher, a
举个例子比如 Cipher  是
cryptography-focused playground,
一个专注密码学的 Playground
we released recently, the
最近刚刚发布的在 Cipher 里
learner's goal is to solve the
学习者的目标是通过
mystery over the course of the
一页页的编程最后揭开一个
pages.
谜题
They find this encrypted note
他们会找到一张加密的便条
and want to figure out what it
然后尝试找到办法破解出
means.
含意
My goal as the author is to get
而我作为编写者我的目标是要
them interested in cryptography
让学习者对密码学产生兴趣
and give them a few new words,
并教给他们一些新的词汇
plain text, ciphertext, just to
比如明文密文之类
spark that interest in a
好激发他们对于另一个
potential discipline.
领域的潜在兴趣
So, keep those goals in mind and
我们要考虑到所有的这些目标
figure out how you can make them
然后找出一个能够让所有目标
intermarry in the best way, to
都有效结合的最好的方式
fully support your learner in
才能给我们的学习者提供一个
their experience.
最好的学习体验
So now, let's walk through some
所以现在我们就一起逐一看看
potential goals that you might
一些我们可能会使用的目标
have, and that we often use in
一些我们可能会设置在
Swift Playgrounds on each page.
Swift Playgrounds 页面上的目标
Completing a task.
完成一项任务
This one's probably the most
这可能是大部分人
familiar to a lot of you.
最熟悉的一个了
We use this a lot in the Learn
我们在"编程学习"里经常
to Codes.
会用到这个目标
Collect all the gems, flip two
收集到所有的宝石啦打开两个
switches, and collect one gem,
开关啦再收集一块宝石啦
place the expert in the right
让专家走到正确的位置啦
These are easy for the learner
学习者很容易就能理解这些
to understand what you want them
目标知道你需要他们去完成些
to do.
什么内容
They have a clear starting
对他们来说这种任务有
point, a clear ending point, and
明确的起点有明确的终点
these are easy for you to
这些目标也很容易
assess, and offer that
评估很容易就可以
personalized-- those
提供出个性化的
personalized hints and
末尾那些个性化的
assessments at the end.
暗示帮助和评估反馈
Experiment.
实验尝试
I love these kind of pages,
我特别喜欢这种页面
because I like to play around
因为我很喜欢用手头的代码
with the code I'm given.
随意进行多种尝试
These are a really good way to
这是个很好用的目标可以
introduce learners to something
帮助我们向学习者介绍一些复杂
complex, to give them a sense of
的概念让他们能够在实际
where they're going before they
编程之前对手头的代码能做什么
dive in to the code.
有一个大致的掌握
We often use this by showing a
通常这种页面的使用方法是
whole big block of code, maybe
先给学习者展示一大段的代码
new functions the learner hasn't
可能有他们还没接触过的
seen yet, maybe new variables,
新函数可能有新的变量
even new concepts, and then we
甚至有新的编程概念但是我们
minimize the amount of code
只开放很小一部分代码
that's actually editable to
可供用户进行修改
them, so they're not overwhelmed
这样学习者就不会觉得哎呀
by seeing, whoa, this is a lot
一下子新信息太多了而觉得
of new stuff.
无法接受
Instead, they can pick out the
然后他们可以自己选出想调整的
parts.
东西
"I know how to change a color, I
比如我知道这样可以改变颜色
know how to change a radius to
或者我知道这样可以把半径改为
negative."
负数
And, they can experiment, and
这样他们就可以动手实验
have fun with this thing that
在真正开始更深入的编程
they're about to dive more
过程之前先玩上一把
deeply into.
熟悉熟悉
Practicing a new skill.
实践练习新技术
I'm hoping you all practice a
我希望大家目前就在
Bill taught us about goal,
Bill 教给了我们
audience, and passion, and I'm
要明确目标要激发热情要了解受众
reiterating that to you now.
我现在就在跟大家一起实践
So, that hopefully when you
这样当我们离开这个演讲的时候
leave this room, you have those
希望我们都能在脑海里
three concepts in your mind.
牢牢记住这三个理念
Learners won't grok a concept
学习者们在一开始接触时不会立即
immediately, the first time.
通过意会领悟到一个概念
You might wish they would, but
你也许希望他们能做到这一点
I'm sure through experience;
但我相信大家都有这样的体验
think back to when you first
回想你第一次
learned a new, complicated
学到一个新的复杂的知识的时候
Could you have written a
你能立即写下它的定义
definition, explained it to one
并向你的同事
of your colleagues immediately?
把它解释清楚吗
No, you needed to practice that
不能你需要反复磨练
skill, to use it in different
这项技能把它用在
contexts so that you can then go
不同的语境中这样你才能
and apply that to some new
进一步去把它运用在
place.
新地方
So, really important to include
所以请切记要
these types of pages in your
把这些页面类型添加进
playground book.
你的 playground 手册里
Think about a concept.
想象一个概念
This one is sort of different.
这有点不同
We talk a lot about code and the
我们说了很多关于每一页上
learner code on each page, but
代码和学习者代码的问题
often in the Learn to Codes and
但在学习代码
the challenges in all of your
和 playground 手册里的
playground books, you're
所有难题中
introducing something totally
你是在介绍一些完全不同的东西
In the cryptography playground,
在 cryptography playground 里
I'm introducing all of
我要介绍关于密码学的
cryptography, and there's
很多知识其中包括
complicated words like
很多复杂词汇比如
ciphertext and key and message.
密文钥匙和消息等等
That's a lot of new information
这对于学习者来说
for a learner to take in.
全新的信息量会很大
And, you want to make sure you
你需要确保
give them that space.
给予他们足够空间
To read, understand, and reflect
去阅读理解
on what you're telling them.
并思考你所教他们的东西
We have several pages that don't
我们有一些页面中
have any user coding on a page,
没有任何用户编码的内容
because those pages are
就因为在这些页面中
concept-heavy.
概念的信息量太大了
And, we want to give the learner
我们想要让学习者
that space.
有消化的空间
Finally, create.
最后一步是创造
These pages are awesome.
这些页面太棒了
This is where you really get to
这里是你展示技巧的地方
show your skills, show what
展示你所学的成果
We've given you, the author, all
我们已经给了你
the tools you need, and now the
作为作者所需要的一切工具
learner is able to go nuts.
现在学习者可以尽情发挥了
They know how to change colors,
他们知道怎么去改变颜色
they know how to add functions,
他们知道怎么去添加功能
they can make the robot dance,
他们可以让机器人翩翩起舞
but they couldn't before.
而此前他们还做不到这些
This is their chance to really
这就是他们去
explore, and to feel empowered.
尽情探索感到自己无所不能的机会
This is why they came to coding.
这就是他们来学习写代码的原因
Why did you all come to coding?
你们为什么要写代码呢
Probably to do something.
大概是要去做点什么
To learn something.
去学点什么
To create something.
去创造点什么
Keep that in mind, that that's
记住这一点
likely what's in your learners'
因为你们的学习者
minds too.
也是这样想的
That they want to create
他们也想要去创造点什么
And so, give them that
因此请赋予他们这个机会吧
Include a wide variety of these
在你们的 playground 中
types of pages in your
添加这些不同类型的页面
playgrounds, and you'll keep
就会让你们的学习者
your learners engaged,
参与感十足
interested, and excited for
并且包含兴趣地
what's coming next.
期待接下来的事情
So, how do we do all of this?
我们要怎样做到这一点呢
How do we get the learner to
我们要怎样帮助学习者
these places?
实现这样的感受呢
How to create these pages?
怎样创造这些页面呢
Well, in Swift Playgrounds
Swift Playgrounds 本身
itself, you have several prose
就自带一些文本工具
tools available to you.
供你们使用
Number one is glossary entries.
首先就是词汇条目(glossary entries)
These are incredibly important
考虑到受众的需要
especially when thinking about
这个工具是非常重要的
Another one of those big,
而另一个至关重要
important points.
的东西
Algorithm might be a simple word
算法 (Algorithm) 对在场的人来说
for all of you, many of you.
是一个很简单的词
You're coders, you're
你们是码农
programmers, you've been around
是程序员
the block, and you know what an
是从业者当然知道算法
algorithm is.
是什么意思
But, a beginner, who's brand new
但对一个刚刚接触
to coding, that's a difficult
写代码的入门者来说这个词就
word.
很难
Something they can't just intuit
他们无法从上下文中
from reading the rest of your
凭直觉猜出这个词的意思
And so, offering this glossary
因此有了这个词汇条目功能
entry, which is triggered in
只需要在
Swift Playgrounds just by
Swift Playgrounds 里
tapping on that differently
点击颜色不同的单词
colored word, gives them the
就可以帮助学习者
support they need to keep on
跟上你们的页面的进度了
Keep in mind, you, as the
需要记住的是
author, are not going to be
身为作者的你
there to pop out of the page,
是无法从页面中跳出来
and tell your learner something
在你的学习者面临困境时
when they're having trouble.
对他们传道解惑的
You need to communicate solely
你只能够通过文本
via the medium of text.
这个唯一的媒介去交流
And so, you want to use all the
因此你必须去用上
tools at your disposal to give
手头的一切工具
extra help where it's needed,
去及时提供额外的帮助
and support your learner in
为你的学习者在进程中
their process.
提供支持
A great way to figure out what
要知道你需要为
kinds of glossary entries you're
哪些词汇建立条目
going to need is by user
一个好办法就是用户测试
Put this in the prototyping
在测试期你可以
stage when you get some prose
写下一些东西
written down in front of
给学习者看
learners, and listen to them.
并听取他们的意见
What words don't they
哪些词是他们
understand?
不懂的呢
What concept did they clearly
他们由于跳过了
not get because they skipped
一个不懂的词
over a vocab word?
而无法理解哪些概念呢
And, include these in your
然后把这些词
glossary entries.
加入到词汇条目中去吧
It's also worth noting, that, if
值得一提的还有
you're localizing your
如果你要本地化你的
playground, you can add
playground 那你最好也
additional glossary entries in
为不同的本地化语言
different localized languages.
建立额外的词汇条目
So, that if there's something
所以如果有一些
jargon-y that maybe an English
词汇也许英语国家的人
speaker would understand, you
能够明白
can offer a glossary entry to
你可以为另一个语言中的这个词
that in another language.
建立词汇条目
So, keep that in mind.
请记住这一点
Take a minute to read this
我们来读一下这条
definition.
定义
You all feel confident about
你们都对
substitution ciphers?
代替密码很自信吗
You could send me a message
你们能现在马上用错过3位的
right now in substitution cipher
代替密码编写出
with a shift of 3?
一条信息发给我吗
What about if I also gave you
如果我再给你们
this diagram?
这幅图表呢
This is much more valuable.
这幅图很有价值
It's helpful to have both,
两者都很有必要
definitely.
毫无疑问
The diagram on its own wouldn't
只有这张图也不行
do it, but just the prose
但是只有那段话
without this visual, impactful
却没有这幅具有视觉冲击力
picture?
的图呢
Is not going to cut it either.
也是完不成任务的
It's so helpful to have visual
在解释复杂概念时
aids in explaining difficult
图表的帮助是非常大的
Do keep in mind, that if you add
一定要记住如果你添加了
visual aids, which you can add
视觉辅助
in that prose section, right in
在文本部分就在文本里面
the prose, that you want to make
就能添加你们一定要保证
sure they have accessibility
它们有 accessibility label
labels, so that your users using
这样那些使用 VoiceOver 的学习者
VoiceOver have just as rich of
就能够享受到
an experience as those who are
和没有使用 VoiceOver 的人
not using VoiceOver.
同样丰富的体验了
Here's a wall of text.
这是一面文本墙
Lots of stuff going on here.
上面有很多东西
Luckily, there's a callout.
幸好有一个 callout
I know which part of this I need
我知道这上面的哪一部分
to pay attention to.
是我需要注意的
Right here, new awesome
就在这儿新的超棒功能
I'm ready to go.
我准备好了
In a lot of our user testing,
在很多用户测试中
users, no matter what age group,
无论哪一个年龄组的用户
what experience level, often
无论他们经验如何
skim the prose.
都会略过文本
They want to get right into
他们只想直接进入
coding, they don't care about
编码他们不在乎你给他们的
all the awesome instructions
那些棒透了的引导和指示
you've given, you've slaved over
而你为了这些东西苦干了
for weeks.
好几周
They just want to get in there
他们一心只想尽快
and write some code.
写上几行代码
And so, support that.
这种需求你也得支持
Give people their tl;dr, too
给他们所谓的tl;dr
long; didn't read it version, in
也就是太长;读不下去
the middle so they can get right
把这个版本放在中间以便让他们
in there.
直接上手
Still, offer them that prose
不过围绕着中间的部分
support, around it.
为他们提供文本支持
If your learner does dive right
如果你的学习者们
in, tries out new awesome
一上来就去尝试
function, and it doesn't do what
新的功能结果却
they expected, they need to be
不像他们预想的那样
able to come back and read about
他们就会想要回来仔细
it, and find out what it does.
读一读弄明白到底怎么回事
It's all about supporting your
要尽一切可能
learner in every aspect you
全方位为学习者
think they might need support.
提供支持
Finally, the shortcut bar.
最后是快捷方式栏
This might not seem like a prose
这看上去不像是个文本
tool, but it's incredibly
工具但它的重要性
important.
非同小可
And you, as the authors, have
身为作者的你
control over what appears in
能够控制这个快捷方式栏上
this shortcut bar.
要显示什么
This is how your learner is
这就是你的学习者
going to start coding.
学习开始写代码的方式
This is how they're doing it on
这就是他们在 iPad 上
an iPad.
学习的方式
Tapping functions, tapping
点击功能
keywords.
点击关键词
This is their main toolbox.
这是他们的主工具箱
So, make it easy to use.
要保证它的易用性
Only include relevant choices.
只保留有关的选项
If your learner's on page tw0 of
如果你的学习者刚刚进行到
your playground book, and you
playground 手册的第二页
have functions from page six and
但你在快捷方式栏上面放了
seven in that shortcut bar,
第六页第七页的功能
that's going to be exhausting
那只会让你的学习者
and distracting.
劳心费力
They're going to have to scroll
他们就得一直翻页
through, finally get to the
好不容易找到
functions they wanted for this
在这一页需要的工具
page, and wonder why they had
不明白为什么
all these extra functions in the
快捷栏中间有这么多用不上的功能
It might even be confusing.
这甚至会造成困扰
Maybe they thought they needed
也许他们会想
to use those other functions.
是不是应该去用这些功能
But, they don't, and now they're
其实根本就不用
not sure.
但现在他们糊涂了
And, you haven't gotten your
同时你也没办法
point across as well as you
顺利地传达你本想传达的
might have.
意思
Use concise method names.
下一点要用简单的方法名
This one can be a little tough,
这会有一点难
because sometimes the method's
因为有的时候
got to say what it's got to say,
方法名必须要表达清楚
but do your best.
但请尽力而为
The one I have here, "shift word
我这里有一个“shift word by”
by," easy, fits on the screen,
很简单适合屏幕宽度
and it's easy for the learner to
学习者也很容易理解
Important to keep your audience
在这里也一定要
in mind here too, in terms of
心中想着受众
what kind of vocabulary you're
去决定要在方法名中
using in these method names.
使用什么样的词汇
Your word choice is just as
你的词汇选择
important as the concepts you're
和你引领他们去
leading them through.
理解的概念一样重要
And, finally, please provide
最后一点请提供
common keywords.
普通关键词
We all love autocomplete.
我们都爱使用自动完成
Your learner will love it if
学习者们如果只需要
they can just tap "func", tap
点击”func”“var”和
"var", tap "if" to put it in
"if" 就能把它放上去他们会很高兴
Don't make them type those over
别让他们反复输入
and over.
这些词
You want to focus on the
要把重点放在
learning, and one of the most
学习上要做到
important things about focusing
这一点最重要的
on the learning is not having
就是不要
ancillary busyness going on in
让你的头脑中
your mind of remembering, was it
满都是需要记住的细枝末节
"func" with a capital F, does
比如那个"func" 的F要不要大写啊
the "var"-- do I need a space
还有那个"var" 我在等号前后
before and after the equals?
需不需要空格啊
Things like that.
这样的事
You don't want to have to deal
你自己都不想去处理
with that, and your learner
这些事你的学习者
doesn't either.
当然也不想
So, just provide these helpful
所以请把这些
things in the shortcut bar, and
都放进快捷栏
your learner will be able to
你的学习者就能够
focus on what you really want to
把注意力集中在
teach them, and that's what
你想教他们的东西上了这是最重要的
So, we've talked about the
我们一直在说
learner, a lot.
学习者
And, that brings us to the
那么接下来就让我们说说
second overarching point.
第二个最重要的事
Who is your learner?
到底谁是学习者
Are they a beginner?
他们是刚刚入门
Are they advanced?
还是已经有一定水平了呢
Are you writing a computational
你是在写一个
biology playground, and showing
计算生物学 playground
it to biologists?
并把它给生物学家看吗
Or, showing it to computer
还是把它给计算机科学家看呢
Those people are going to bring
不同人群的背景
totally different backgrounds
和经验水平
and experience levels.
是完全不一样的
And, you really need to get to
你真的需要
know your learner and understand
了解你的学习者
where they're coming from to
了解他们的背景
provide them the best, richest,
才能够给他们以
most supportive learning
最好最丰富最有帮助的
experience.
学习体验
I'm going to walk you through
现在我就带你们
some examples now, of pages from
看一些例子
our playground books where we
这是我们 playground 手册中的一些页面
had goals in mind, but we also
在这里我们有自己的目标
had to keep our audience
但同时也要时时刻刻
strongly in the forefront.
考虑到我们的受众
This is a page from Learn to
这是编程学习 3 中的一页
Code 3, where we're asking the
我们在这里要求
learner to add a background
学习者在屏幕上添加
image to the screen.
一张背景图
We say it right there.
我们在这里提出要求
Set a background image.
设置一张背景图
Add it to the screen.
把它添加到屏幕上
And, that's because this is
因为这里的目标受众
targeted at a beginner.
是初学者
Complete a task-style goal, like
完成一个任务目标
we talked about from before, and
就像我们之前说过的
beginner audience.
初学者受众
Set a background image, alright,
设置背景图好的
I'm primed.
我准备好了
And now, right here, this is how
接下来在这里
you do it.
你需要这么做
scene.backgroundImage equals
scene.backgroundImage 等号
"image literal."
"image literal"
I give the learner the syntax,
我要教给学习者语法
because, again, this is targeted
因为这里的目标受众是
at a beginner who's not going to
初学者他们
have all that far-reaching
没有那么多
computer science knowledge, not
渊博的计算机科学知识
even that far-reaching.
都不用渊博
To us, this seems simple.
对咱们来说这太简单了
Everyone knows that
人人都知道
"backgroundImage" is the name of
"backgroundImage" 是那个
that property.
属性的名字
But a beginner doesn't.
但初学者不知道
And since we're all content
因为我们都是
matter experts, it's really hard
内容专家所以很难
to put ourselves in the shoes of
把去设身处地地
a beginner who isn't familiar
从初学者角度看问题
with the syntax.
他们不熟悉语法
That's why user testing is so
因此用户测试才
important.
这么重要
To figure out what kind of
要明白你们之间
logical leaps you're making,
理解的差异
that your learner needs to be
要为你的学习者们
walked through a little more
提供更加详细的
slowly.
指导
We then give them extremely
要给他们
explicit instructions.
极为明确的指示
Write the syntax we just gave
写下我们刚才
you, and then choose "image
给你的语法然后从快捷栏里选择
literal" from the shortcut bar.
“Image literal”
Again, we're offering them the
我们为他们在快捷栏里
appropriate shortcuts in the
提供合适的快捷方式
bar, and then choose a
然后选择一个
background image.
背景图
By now, you are probably all,
现在你们可能觉得
like, I know, background image,
我知道啦背景图嘛
I'm good, move on.
我都明白继续吧
But, a beginner needs this
但要记住初学者就是需要
support.
这种支持
Finally, we even offer a
最后我们还提供了
comment.
评论功能
This is where you do it, this is
这里就是那个地方
where you write the code.
就是你写下代码的地方
Set background image.
设定背景图片
Let's take a look at a page with
我们来看一个页面
a similar goal, completing a
目的是类似的完成一个任务
task, but with a totally
但这次的受众
different audience in mind.
是完全不同的
These are your advanced
这次是进阶学习者
We still have a goal statement,
我们还是有一个目标说明
but it's far more broad.
但它要远比刚才那个更具概括性
Use a breadth-first search
使用广度优先算法
algorithm to complete the maze.
完成这个解谜
There are any number of ways
我可以用很多方式
that I could complete this.
完成这个任务
And, I have to have a lot of
我必须要在头脑中
knowledge in my brain already to
具备很多知识
even understand what that goal
才能够明白
statement means.
这个目标说明的意义
We still offer instructions, but
我们还是会提供指示
again, they're more broad, more
但这些指示也更概况
open-ended.
更开放式了
Start by adding all the tiles to
首先将所有砖块
the queue.
加入队列
Pop those tiles.
敲击砖块
And there you go.
然后就完成了
And then, in the user code
然后在用户代码区
section, we just offer an empty
我们仅提供了一个
function and ask the user to use
空白功能并让用户
their knowledge that they
用他们已有的知识
already have, that we've taught
我们所教给他们的知识
them a little bit of, to do
去完成这个
Totally open-ended, overwhelming
完全开放式的
for a beginner, but for an
对初学者来说太难
advanced learner, they know what
但对进阶学习者来说他们会知道该怎么做
to do.
他们知道要如何完成
task, and move on with the page.
这个任务继续下面的页面
What about a different style of
换一个不同风格的页面怎么样
Thinking about a concept.
试想一个概念
In this one, we introduce Blink,
在这里我们要介绍 Blink
related to Conway's Game of
这取材于康威的生命游戏
Life, which is essentially a
那基本上是一个细胞模拟器
cell simulator, where cells live
细胞生存死亡
and die depending on how many
取决于周围有
neighbors they have around them.
多少相邻的细胞
It's a pretty complicated idea,
那是个很复杂的概念
that can be broken down into
但可以被打散成
simple rules.
简单的规则
We give the learner a fair
我们在这里给了学习者
amount of text here, because
花了不少篇幅解释
we're introducing something
因为我们在介绍
totally new.
全新的东西
And, that's part of our job, is
我们工作的一部分
to explain that in detail, for
就是去详细解释
those who are interested.
给那些感兴趣的人
We do have a goal statement, but
我们有一个目标说明
it's embedded, and the goal is
但它是隐含在里面的
just to really understand these
目标就是要真正明白
algorithms, to think.
这些算法去思考
There's no clear end point, no
没有明确的终点
time where the page tells you
不会让页面告诉你
you're ready to move on.
你可以继续了
It's up to you, to understand
全都取决于你
this, play around with the live
去更多地了解这个
view, which you'll see in a
去玩一下 live view 很快就会展示
minute.
并作为一个学习者
ready, as the learner.
自己去领悟什么时候已经准备好了
We still offer this sort of
我们还是在中间
tl;dr version in the middle.
给出了这个“太长；不读”版本
If you didn't want to read all
如果你不想读上面那些
that prose at the top, here are
文本那就读这些
the rules of the simulation.
模拟的规则吧
You can kind of get where you're
你读了这些就差不多明白
going with these.
要做什么了
So, it's somewhat similar
所以这是一个
structure to completing a task,
完成任务的类似结构
but a totally different learner
但有着完全不同的学习者目标
goal, and author goal.
和作者目标
And then, finally, we have, kind
最后我们在底部
of instructions, at the bottom.
还有可算是指示的东西
They're embedded, again.
它们同样也是隐含的
Experiment with stepping through
在模拟过程中依照步骤
the simulation, which we've
做实验这我们也在
provided on the live view side.
live view里提供了
Try it out, and then when you're
去试一试你们准备好之后
ready, go on to the next page to
就去下一个页面
explore what you'll be doing
看看你们用它能
with it.
做什么吧
What's the audience of this
这一页的受众又是谁呢
Is it advanced?
进阶学习者吗
Beginner? Are they science
初学者吗是学理科的学生吗
Are they artists?
是艺术家吗？（文科生或者？）
The way you're going to figure
要弄清楚受众的身份
that out is, you have your
你必须时刻想着
target audience in mind, and
受众然后去
then you need to do user
进行受众调查
Find out if this is too
调查明白这对他们来说
complicated for them.
是不是太复杂了
Figure out what words need to be
要弄明白哪些词汇是需要解释的
defined, what concepts need to
哪些概念是需要多作说明的
be explained more, or perhaps
哪些又是不用多说的
Don't underestimate your
也不要过分
audience either.
低估了你的受众
Is it coding time yet?
到了写代码的时候了吗
We've got all these ideas, we
我们有这些想法
understand the goal, the
我们明白目标
audience.
明白受众
We know all the parts of the
我们熟悉了 playground 页面的
playground page, backward and
所有部分前前后后
Surely, it must be coding time
当然现在一定是该写代码了
Not yet. I've moved from my
还不到时候我关上
little notebook to my
小笔记本
whiteboard, but that's it.
拿出白板这就完了
I have expanded my ideas
我扩展了我的想法
somewhat.
我写下了一些文本
I have the coding section, I
我有了代码区
have transitions.
还有过渡区
Also, in this format, I can talk
在这种形式下
to some of my co-workers in the
我可以与办公室的一些同事进行讨论
Hey, Alex, does this make any
嘿 Alex 你看得懂
sense to you?
这个吗
What do you think?
你怎么想
Is this a cool idea, Bill?
这个点子够酷吗 Bill
Would your kids like this?
你的孩子会喜欢它吗
It's really important to get
要从真实用户口中
feedback from your actual users,
得到反馈这非常重要
and from your colleagues, your
还有你的同事你的同级
This is your prototyping phase,
这是你的原型阶段
to figure out what works and
要弄明白哪些有用
what doesn't.
哪些行不通
So, no, it is not coding time
所以不现在还不是写代码的时候
So, we've talked through goal
我们讲过了目标
and audience, and it's time to
和受众现在要
talk about passion.
讲一讲热情了
Passion is so important.
热情非常重要
This should be threaded
它应该贯穿
throughout all your other
你所有的 playground
playground prototyping and
原型与思考阶段
Why are you even doing this?
你为什么要做这个呢
Why are you writing a
为什么要写一个
playground?
playground 呢
It's because you're passionate
因为你满怀热情地
about something that you want to
要去分享一些东西
share, that you want to teach to
要去交给别人
someone else.
一些东西
If you're not passionate about
如果你对你写 playground 的东西
what you're writing a playground
毫无热情
about, why are you doing it?
那你为什么要去做这事呢
And that, that not passion is
那种毫无热情
going to show through, and your
必将显示出来
learner's not care either.
而学习者也会毫不关心你做的东西
So, bringing your passion to
所以一定要拿出热情
this is so important.
这无比重要
How can you do this?
你该怎么做呢
Well, let's take a look at the
我们来看一看
live view.
live view
I said this before, this is
我之前说过
where the learner is going to
在这个部分里学习者会
get to experience their code
去体验到他们的代码
running.
实际运行
This is where they're going to
在这里他们会
get excited about creating,
非常激动地看到
about what they've made.
他们所创造的东西
So, this is your chance to make
在这里你可以
that experience as visually
把那种激动的经验
exciting, as auditorily
视觉化
exciting, as exciting period,
把它听觉化
for your users.
让你的用户也同样激动
Here's Learn to Code, where we
这里是编程学习
have this adorable character,
我们有这个可爱的人物
this cool, game-style world.
这个超酷的游戏般的世界
This appeals to a lot of people.
这会吸引到很多人的喜爱
Gets them excited about jumping
让他们满怀激动地
into this world and writing
跳进这个世界学习写代码
Here's another example of
这是另一个例子
spirals.
螺旋
I had so much fun working on
我用它体会到了超多乐趣
this, I would get totally
我在试图 debug 的时候
distracted trying to de-bug by
甚至会分心去
just creating cool new spirals
制造新的超酷螺旋
and modifying variables.
修改变量
That's a great sign.
这是个很棒的预兆
If you enjoy going through the
如果你自己很享受
tasks in your playground book,
playground 手册里的任务
your learners probably will too.
那你的学习者们估计也会一样的
And, on the other hand, if
另一方面
you're bored by the exercises,
如果你对这些练习感到无聊
if you wonder why you're
如果你自己都不知道自己
teaching this, how are you going
为什么要教这个
to get your learner motivated to
那你又怎么去让学习者们有动力
go through them either?
去完成这些学习任务呢
You have to be excited about
你一定要对自己做的事
what you're doing, to bring your
感到激动要把你的热情
passion to those views.
带到这里面来
Here's another cool example,
这是另一个很酷的例子
totally different style.
完全不同的风格
This is, Blink.
这是Blink
From that page of text you saw
就是大家刚才看到的页面上的
We have all that text, but we
我们有了所有的文本
also have this rich,
但同时我们也有右边这个
interactive, live view on the
丰富的交互式的
right hand side, where the
live view
learner can play with the
在这里学习者可以
algorithm, they can use touch
“玩”算法他们可以
gestures to interact with it.
用触屏手势与它互动
This is the place where passion
在这里热情
can really shine.
真正会闪耀
So. We have the marriage of
我们有了 Bill 给你们讲的
teaching that Bill talked to you
教学还有我给你们讲的
about, and designing that I
设计然后
talked to you about.
把这两者结合在一起
It's so important to keep these
最重要是要把这些
in mind, the teaching aspect,
记在心里教学的方面
what you're trying to get
你想要传达的东西
across, and how you're designing
以及你是如何设计它的
it.
如何去测试原型的
Who you're talking to for help,
你在与谁对话
how often you're user testing.
你进行用户测试的频率如何
With these two-- when these
有了这两者的结合
powers combine, we are Captain
我们都可以变成
Amazing Teacher.
伟大的老师
So. Get ready for it.
所以准备好吧
Coding time.
编码时间
[ Applause ]
[ 掌声 ]
Once you have your prototype, or
有了原型之后
excuse me, storyboard figured
或者说故事板设计好之后
out.
有了反馈
talked to your users, talked to
与用户交谈过
whoever wanted you to make this
与那些一开始要求你
playground in the first place,
制作 playground 的人交谈过
if it wasn't you.
如果那个人不是你的话
You've gotten all those things
在所有这一切完成之后
together, you know what you want
你会知道该去
your hints to be, you know what
暗示什么
you want your success messages
你会知道你的成功信息是什么
to be, how you're going to
如何以最好的方式
assist your learner in all the
去为你的学习者们
best ways.
提供帮助
You've got a storyboard, now it
你有了一个故事板
is time for you to write code,
现在你该写代码了
and make that awesome playground
让那个超棒的 playground
idea a reality.
创意成真
And, you don't need me to teach
我知道你们根本不需要我教你们
you how to code.
如何写代码
So, you can probably all say it
你们也许已经听腻了
with me now at this point, but
但还是要说
the three things to take away
这场演示的三大要点
from this presentation are goal,
明确目标了解受众
audience, and passion.
和激发热情
That's right.
没错
And so, with those things in
那么在记住这些之后
mind, I say to you all, go
我要对大家说
forth, and teach.
放手去教吧
[ Applause ]
[ 掌声 ]
If you're interested, the slides
如果你们感兴趣
and transcripts and all that
这场的幻灯片演讲稿
good stuff will be available on
一切干货都能
our WWDC website.
在 WWDC 网站上找到
There were some related--
今年还有一些与此有关的
awesome related sessions this
超棒的演讲
year, which have all passed, but
虽然都已经讲过了
you can watch them online.
但你可以在网上看到它们
And so, thank you all so much
谢谢大家来听演讲
I wish you safe travels back to
希望大家回家
your homes.
一路平安
And I can't wait to see you all
我已经迫不及待再次见到你们
next year at WWDC 2018.
就在明年的 WWDC 2018
[ Applause ]
[ 掌声 ]